A Finding Aid to the Sue Pierce papers relating to the exhibition Full Deck Art Quilts, 1988-2002, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
Sue Pierce papers relating to the exhibition Full Deck Art Quilts
1988- 2002
Archives of American Art
Pierce, Sue
AAA.piersue
Archival Resource Key
1.4 Linear feet
The papers of quiltmaker and curator Sue Pierce relating to the exhibition Full Deck Art Quilts measure 1.4 linear feet, date from 1988 to 2002, and comprise material Pierce collected as curator of the exhibition.
Biographical / Historical
Sue Pierce is a quiltmaker and curator in Rockville, Maryland.
Pierce received a Bachelor of Arts degree in math from Duke University in 1965. She found that she enjoyed experimenting with fabrics when she created a quilt as a wedding gift for her brother in 1975. In 1985, she rented studio space to focus on her art full time. In 1992, Pierce began gathering material for the Full Deck project, in which 54 quilters were chosen to pick a unique playing card and interpret the card in a quilt. The project culminated in the exhibition, Full Deck Art Quilts, that opened in 1995 at the Smithsonian's Renwick Gallery, with a catalog written by Verna Suit. Smithsonian Institution Traveling Exhibition Service (SITES) then circulated the exhibition across the country.
Pierce's work is in the collections of the author Tom Wolfe, the U.S. Department of State, National Institutes of Health, and others. She is a member of the American Craft Council, Studio Art Quilt Association, and Art Quilt Network/New York, and was a founding board member of Arts Place.
Arrangement
Due to the small size of this collection the papers are arranged as one series.
Scope and Contents
The papers of quiltmaker and curator Sue Pierce relating to the exhibition Full Deck Art Quilts measure 1.4 linear feet, date from 1988 to 2002, and comprise material Pierce collected as curator of the exhibition. The majority of the collection consists of files for each of the 54 participating artists containing correspondence, resumes, painted fabric samples, photographs, printed materials, questionnaires regarding participation in the exhibition, sketches, and artist statements. Other files contain correspondence, an exhibition proposal, photographs and captions, and printed materials. Printed materials include the exhibition catalog, Art Quilts: Playing with a Full Deck, 2 decks of playing cards featuring quilts from the exhibition, the calendar Face Cards from Art Quilts: Playing with a Full Deck, clippings, and other related material.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. Access to original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C. Research Center.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was donated in 2002 by Sue Pierce as part of the Nanette L. Laitman Documentation Project for Craft and Decorative Arts in America.
Quiltmakers -- Maryland -- Rockville; Art museum curators -- Maryland -- Rockville; American studio craft movement; Drawings; Women artists; Suit, Verna; Full Deck (Project); Nanette L. Laitman Documentation Project for Craft and Decorative Arts in America
- Sue Pierce Papers Relating to the Exhibition Full Deck Art Quilts, 1988-2002; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 1.4 Linear feet Boxes 1-2, OVs 3-4
  Scope and Contents
  Series comprises material Pierce collected as curator of the exhibition, including artist files for the 54 participating artists, and printed material. Artist files contain correspondence, resumes, painted fabric samples, photographs, printed materials, questionnaires regarding participation in the exhibition, sketches, and artist statements.
  Other files contain correspondence, an exhibition proposal, photographs and captions, and printed materials that include the exhibition catalog written by Pierce and Verna Suit, Art Quilts: Playing with a Full Deck, 2 decks of playing cards featuring quilts from the exhibition, the calendar Face Cards from Art Quilts: Playing with a Full Deck, clippings, and other printed material related to the exhibition. Handwritten notes by Pierce can be found throughout the collection and provide additional information on the records.
  - Adams, B.J., 1992-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Anderson, Deborah, 1993-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Autenrieth, Pat, 1992-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Becker, Judy, 1990-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Benson, Jeanne, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Berkenfeld, Karen Felicity, 1992-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Brainard, Katharine, 1992-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Brown, Sara, 1993-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Brown, Tafi, 1992-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Busch, Elizabeth A., 1990-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Carey, Joyce Marquess, 1992-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Cochran, Jane Burch, 1993-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Danley-Brown, Dee, 1992-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Davis, Ardyth, 1992-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Davis, Lenore, 1993-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Edmonds, Chris Wolf, 1993-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Faeder, Susan B., 1992-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Fallert, Caryl Bryer, 1993-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Fraas, Gayle and Duncan Slade, 1993-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Gersen, Carol H., 1992-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Hawkins, Patty, 1991-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Herbort, Diane, 1993-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Holden, Dorothy, 1992-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Holzinger, Melissa, 1993-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Humberson, Sandra, 1992-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Junker, Holly, 1993-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Kempers-Cullen, Natasha, 1992-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Knaver, Katherine, 1992-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Laury, Jean Ray, 1993-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Lawler, Mickey, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Lawler, Mickey, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 4)
  - Lehman, Libby, 1993-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Levin, Linda, 1992-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Lintault, M. Joan, 1993-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - MacDonald, Linda, 1993-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Malwitz, Marguerite Ann, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Mangat, Terri, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 36)
    Mangat was originally chosen to create a quilt but was ultimately unable to participate and was replaced by Katharine Brainard.
  - May, Therese, 1991-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Mazloomi, Carolyn L., 1993-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - McKearn, Katherine, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Mortenson, Barbara, 1993-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Nash, Dominie, 1993-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - O'Connor, Kathleen, 1993-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Perry, Linda, 1993-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Pierce, Sue, 1992-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Porcella, Yvonne, 1993-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Richardson, Emily, 1993-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Scherer, Deidre, 1988-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Schulze, Joan, 1993-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Schwalb, Robin, 1992-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Sharp, Kathleen, 1993-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Shie, Susan and James Acord, 1993-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Shurtliff, Jen, 1992-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Shurtliff, Jen, 1992-1993; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 3, Folder 1)
  - Suit, Verna (Catalog Author), 1993-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Sward, Lynne, circa 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Vernon, Michele, 1991-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Williamson, Jeanne, 1993-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Williamson, Jeanne, 1993-1995; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Artists Who Declined to Participate, 1992-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Correspondence, Mailings to Artists, 1992-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Correspondence, General, 1993-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Exhibition Proposal, 1992-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Photographs and Captions, circa 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Printed Materials, Calendar Face Cards from Art Quilts: Playing with a Full Deck, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 3, Folder 3)
  - Printed Materials, Clippings, 1995-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Printed Materials, Exhibition Catalog Art Quilts: Playing with a Full Deck, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Printed Materials, Exhibition Playing Card Decks, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 3)
    2 decks
  - Printed Materials, Miscellaneous Exhibition Material, 1993-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 4)